

# **Jyotirmayi Swain**

(+49) 15124884481 | jyotirmayi.swain@gmail.com

1 OG links, Vollmerhausen, Lachtstr. 16, 51645, Gummersbach, Germany About me:

I am a Frontend Engineer with 7.5 years of total IT experience who loves learning and keeping myself updated. At the moment I am upgrading my skills learning from Udemy and watching Youtube videos after quitting my last Job. **Available to join immediately**. I would rate myself **4 out of 5** for the following technologies - React JS, Javascript, HTML and CSS.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

Gummersbach, Germany

## **WEB DEVELOPER**

A passionate and versatile Frontend Engineer specializing in React JS for developing scalable and user focused applications, dedicated to meet deadlines and produce exemplary results, in a dynamic environment .

03/10/2019 - 19/11/2021 - Bangalore, India

# **TECHNOLOGY ANALYST - TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES**

- Handle Frontend development with business logic implementation for each of the project components
- Experience in designing and developing responsive, highly performant and reliable Reactbased web Applications
- Experience in fetching data from API endpoints and showcasing it on the responsive application usable on varied range of devices e.g. laptop, tablet, mobiles
- Collaborate closely with other teams to deliver high value to the end-user
- Design and develop landing pages, dashboards and new features on a webpage using HTML,
  CSS, Javascript ES6 and React based on a wireframe
- Experience with functional asynchronous programming and Rest API
- Comfortable in using GIT to manage built Application versions and collaborate with team
- Passion for learning and mastering new skills
- Extremely strong sense of ownership and personal accountability
- Excellent written and verbal communication skills in English and A2 level of German
- Strong understanding of business goals and self motivated to achieve the objectives to bring outcomes in time bound manner
- Following are 3 of my projects for reference built using React JS, HTML5 and CSS:
- <a href="https://moviesanimated.herokuapp.com/">https://moviesanimated.herokuapp.com/</a>
- https://jyoti28490.github.io/Airbnb-clone/
- https://jyoti28490.github.io/Netflix-Clone/

17/09/2018 - 01/10/2019 - Bangalore, India

#### **IT ANALYST - INFOSYS**

- Involved in fixing bugs opened by client and helped in bringing down the bugs by 70% by automating common issues
- Proactively communicated with all levels of employees to facilitate systems administration and resolved 80 % problem tickets

- Reduced 30% of recurring incident tickets using powershell scripting
- Coordinated with management teams to plan, develop, align and execute strategies that would meet client's vision, mission and purpose

08/05/2014 - 04/09/2018 - Bangalore, India

#### **SYSTEM ENGINEER - TECH MAHINDRA**

- Resolved incidents and problem tickets .Spearheaded compliance efforts for over 2000 enterprise servers and involved in solely managing the Enterprise Citrix farm
- Resolved issues and escalated problems with knowledgeable support and quality service
- Communicated status updates to affected parties when issues arose
- Spearheaded compliance efforts for over 2000 servers and developed best practices to drive continual process improvements for security and application compliance with enterprise servers

# EDUCATION AND TRAINING

18/06/2008 - 18/06/2012

**BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN ELECTRONICS AND TELECOMMUNICATION** – Bij u Patnaik University of Technology

2012-2014: Preparing for GATE

# DIGITAL SKILLS

Git | RESTful api | HTML5/CSS, Javascript | React Hooks / React Bootstrap / React Router / React Hooks

## LANGUAGE SKILLS

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C2	C2	C2	C2	C2
GERMAN	A2	A2	A1	A1	A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user